<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>
  <header>About Aranym</header>
  <chapter>
    <title>Aranym's Goal</title>
    <text>

Aranym's goal is to create new open TOS compatible operating system
easily portable to various architectures and thus allow all ST/TT/Falcon
users to upgrade to incomparably more powerful and up-to-date machines
where they could continue working in their favourite environment using
popular applications with no restrictions known from old TOS machines
or their emulators.

    </text>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <title>Final Product</title>
    <text>

Final product, in conjuction with modern hardware (primarily cheap x86 machines),
will bring you possibilities and power undreamed-of on real
m68k machine. Thanks to that you'll be able to make full use of the potential
of most current applications. Besides that a new vast space will be opened 
for porting of new applications from other platforms (thanks to MiNT
and newly also X11 for GEM and libSDL for TOS this is already very easy
but it is not yet happening because of low power of old TOS machines). On Aranym
these new applications will run with real speed.

    </text>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <title>Dreams come true</title>
    <text>

Have you ever dreamt about watching MPEG/DivX videos, MP3 encoding, playing games
in emulators of various computers/game consoles or e.g. to surf Internet using
the high-end WEB browsers? With Aranym all this will be possible! Plus you'll get
all those great applications in comfortable GEM environment you got used to. 
That is Aranym - the future of TOS platform.

    </text>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <title>TOS is unnecessary</title>
    <text>

Notice: in early stage of Aranym development (which is just coming to its end)
the original TOS 4.04 Falcon ROM image is used and also some necessary Falcon
hardware is emulated. That, plus certain not well thought/written phrases published
on our WEB led our readers to a feeling that Aranym is a Falcon emulator. That is not true.
This development phase is there only to develop native drivers that will completely
replace (in some cases already replaced) the original emulated parts of the machine.
<p/>
And thanks to the EmuTOS project we will be able to get rid of the original copyrighted Atari
TOS ROM. Future Aranym versions will not require any TOS and will not emulate any 
unnecessary Atari hardware. Instead, they will fully profit from other OpenSource projects
like are EmuTOS, FreeMiNT, fVDI, XaAES and others.

    </text>
  </chapter>
</document>
