<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>
  <header>Frequently Asked Questions</header>
  <chapter>
    <title>What is ARAnyM?</title>
    <text>
      ARAnyM is an acronym. It means "Atari Running on Any Machine".
      The main goal of the project is to create a virtual machine
      that would allow anyone to install, use and also <B>develop new</B> 32bit Atari ST/TT/Falcon
      applications on their computer regardless of its architecture.
    </text>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <title>What ARAnyM is NOT?</title>
    <text>
      ARAnyM has never been designed as a complete emulator of any
      Atari machine. Thus we don't like to use the word "emulator" when
      talking about the ARAnyM. ARAnyM emulates only the hardware essentially
      needed for booting the TOS ROM and MiNT in consequence. If you intended
      to play games and (or) launch demos made for ST/Falcon then just forget
      ARAnyM and install some existing emulator created for this purpose
      (STonX, WinSTon, Steem, etc..)
    </text>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <title>Why did we start ARAnyM?</title>
    <text>
      The TOS compatible platform hardware goes slightly away from scene.
      The Atari hardware products and their clones are one big, nearly
      closed, dying chapter of the TOS platform. The last abitious project,
      Milan II computer, had given it up in late 2000.
      Existing machines are of a rather low performace in comparison with
      any other up-to-date platform. The peripheral development is also
      stopped. On the other hand there exist a big bunch of
      modern applications and quite modern OS with a big potential power.
      These are the things that we would like to keep alive and not to throw
      them away with the old slow hardware stuff. ARAnyM gives the TOS
      platform the ultimate possibility to live on and to take the advantage
      of all features of current modern computer hardware.
    </text>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <title>Does MiNT or MagiC work?</title>
    <text>
      Yes, ARAnyM was primarily created to allow users run MiNT (even with
      memory protection). ARAnyM virtualizes the HW the way
      that MagiC works as well. Basically every application cleanly programmed to
      be TOS compliant should work. Please <contact>let us know</contact> if your
      application does not run under ARAnyM.
    </text>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <title>How does it work?</title>
    <text>
      You simply turn on your host machine (PC, Mac, Sun, whatever) and after
      a while of booting (when the Fuji logo shines on the screen)
      you end up in your favourite GEM desktop. In the background the 
      HostOS booted up (we use Linux for now but ARAnyM can be ported to
      any OS) and started the ARAnyM, which now emulates MC68040 CPU, FPU and
      a couple of other Falcon030 chips so that a slightly patched TOS 4.04 boots
      and runs your favourite Atari software. This is the ideal state (see also the <A HREF="#distribution">Distribution</A>)
      for the 'ARAnyM only' mode of operation. We, while developing ARAnyM, use it in so called application mode when the Atari runs in a window on regular X11 Host desktop.


      For conversion from your old Atari machine to this new powerful ARAnyM virtual machine
      you simply take your Atari harddrive and put it into your new machine. Or you can create
      a disk image of your working harddrive and work with that in ARAnyM. If you never
      had a hard drive connected to your old Atari computer you can create an empty virtual
      disk or use a physical one dedicated just to Atari software.
     
    </text>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <title>How does it work? (Technical)</title>
    <text>
      As said. There is a 040 CPU core taken from the UAE (Unix Amiga Emulator).
      The MMU and some patches were added to it. The other emulated chips are
      mainly ACIA, BLITTER, Falcon VIDEL and IDE and basic input peripherals
      handled by MFP (respective IKBD) like keyboard and mouse.
      Afterburner 040 TOS is used. So ARAnyM is actually a <B>Virtual AFTERBURNER040</B>.
      The whole system runs on Host OS (primarily Linux, in future
      maybe Windows, Mac, etc.). Linux system (we call it more generally "Host OS") is
      installed before ARAnyM and after that it is "invisible" to the user. That
      means that ARAnyM user wouldn't nearly notice its presence. It is also possible
      to install ARAnyM in so called "application mode" to already installed and being
      used Host OS. After that you can start ARAnyM like a normal Host OS application in
      its own window and work with it like with other emulators.
    </text>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <title>What are the aims in the ARAnyM future development?</title>
    <text>
      Step by step should the missing features be added. These are sound support,
      accelerated graphics, I/O ports, etc. The copyright free system should be ideally
      reached. The main licencing problem is the TOS ROM copyright and so a new "ROM"
      should be created just to enable to boot into the Atari FreeMiNT OS. After that
      we would get a multitasking, multiuser, GEM compatible ARAnyM system free
      of all copyright issues, licensed under the GPL! The next steps should be a deeper
      integration of other OS parts (FreeMiNT, fVDI, XaAES, Desktop). In future some
      parts of these might run natively in Host OS platform machine code. In a far future
      there can be a totally native ARAnyM system in that could the Host OS native
      applications be compiled and used in cooperation with 68k ones. The Macintosh does
      this (m68k and PowerPC mix) and so it could work for us, too.
    </text>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <a name="distribution"/>
    <title>Distribution</title>
    <text>
      The standalone distribution should be created to simplify the installation process.
      This distribution should comprise all components needed to make use of all advantages
      of the hardware used. The Host OS installation (preferably Linux) as the base followed
      by the ARAnyM application itself further to complete MiNT installation including VDI,
      AES and Desktop. The distribution should contain all tools and applications needed
      to install ARAnyM on a PC hardware. This includes partitioning tools, peripheral setup tools,
      network setup etc. All these in a user friendly enviroment, so that a regular user could
      handle that.
    </text>
  </chapter>
</document>
